<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Enclosed on Deuts Log</title>
    <link>https://deuts.org/a/enclosed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Enclosed on Deuts Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 Deuts Log</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:13:09 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://deuts.org/a/enclosed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enclosed could be the best PrivateBin replacement</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/enclosed-privatebin-alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:13:09 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/enclosed-privatebin-alternative/</guid>
      <description>My thoughts on Enclosed, a minimalistic and secure web app for private note sharing, and why it’s a strong contender to replace PrivateBin in my workflow. </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://github.com/CorentinTh/enclosed">Enclosed</a></strong> is a minimalistic web application designed for sending private and secure notes.</p>
<p>All notes are end-to-end encrypted, ensuring that the server and storage have zero knowledge of the content. You can set a password, define an expiration period (TTL), and choose to have the note self-destruct after being read.</p>
<h3 id="a-promising-alternative-to-privatebin">A Promising Alternative to PrivateBin</h3>
<p>I’ve been using <a class="applink" href="https://deuts.org/a/privatebin" target="_blank">PrivateBin</a> for secure note sharing, but its outdated interface often left me wishing for a modernized alternative. <a class="applink" href="https://deuts.org/a/enclosed" target="_blank">Enclosed</a>, with its elegant default dark theme and minimalist design, feels like a breath of fresh air.</p>
<p>While I haven’t completely switched yet, I’m seriously contemplating making Enclosed my primary tool. It addresses several pain points I had with PrivateBin, such as:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>A Modern, Elegant Interface:</strong> Enclosed stays true to its design philosophy, providing a clean and visually appealing experience.</li>
<li><strong>Improved Reliability:</strong> I often faced issues with PrivateBin where pastes would disappear after upgrades. I’m optimistic that Enclosed won’t suffer from the same problem, given its well-thought-out implementation.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="features-that-won-me-over">Features That Won Me Over</h3>
<p>Two recent updates in the last month to Enclosed particularly impressed me:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Restricting Note Creation to Logged-In Users:</strong> This feature adds an extra layer of control, making the platform more secure.</li>
<li><strong>No Expiration Option:</strong> Previously, expiration periods were limited to 1 hour, 1 day, 1 week, or 1 month. Now, I can set notes to never expire, which is perfect for more persistent needs.</li>
</ol>
<p>These enhancements show the developer’s commitment to refining the app and meeting user needs, making Enclosed a very attractive alternative.</p>
<h3 id="my-wishlist-for-enclosed">My Wishlist for Enclosed</h3>
<p>While Enclosed has been a joy to use so far, there are a few features I’d love to see added:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Deleting Shared Notes:</strong> As a logged-in user, I’d like the option to delete notes I’ve shared, provided I know the key.</li>
<li><strong>More Formatting Options:</strong> Just like PrivateBin allows formatting pastes as markdown, plaintext, or source code, I hope Enclosed adds similar options—and ideally, supports even more formats.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h3>
<p>Enclosed isn’t just a potential replacement for PrivateBin—it could become the best tool for secure note sharing. While I’m still evaluating it, the updates and overall experience have made a strong case for switching for good.</p>
<p>If you’re exploring alternatives for PrivateBin or looking for a secure, modern solution for note sharing, Enclosed is definitely worth a try.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
