<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Speakers on Deuts Log</title>
    <link>https://deuts.org/t/speakers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speakers on Deuts Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 Deuts Log</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 13:34:36 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://deuts.org/t/speakers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Bluetooth Speakers Losing Their Built-In Microphones?</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/bluetooth-speaker-built-in-mic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 13:34:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/bluetooth-speaker-built-in-mic/</guid>
      <description>Bluetooth speakers are increasingly losing built-in microphones, reducing their versatility for online meetings. Possible motivations for this change include cost-cutting and focusing on core features, which creates challenges for mobile users unable to separate mic and audio functions.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bluetooth speakers used to come with built-in microphones, like the JBL Go 1, making them perfect for online meetings and calls. But starting with newer models like the JBL Go 3, manufacturers have dropped this feature—and it’s frustrating. Why might this be happening?</p>
<p>One reason could be cost-cutting. Adding a microphone requires extra hardware and software like noise cancellation, which might not be worth the expense for manufacturers if most users aren’t using it. It’s also possible that companies want to simplify their devices, focusing on sound quality and portability instead of trying to make them all-purpose tools.</p>
<p>Another possibility is that manufacturers don’t want Bluetooth speakers to overlap with other products like smart speakers or earbuds, which are better suited for calls. Removing the mic helps clearly position Bluetooth speakers as music devices and avoids complaints about call quality or compatibility issues.</p>
<p>But for people like me, this design shift creates a real problem. If you use a mobile device like an Android phone or tablet for online meetings, a Bluetooth speaker without a mic is practically useless. You can’t separate the audio and mic functions, meaning you’re forced to either use the phone’s built-in speaker or switch to headphones. This limitation doesn’t exist on laptops, where you can mix and match input and output devices more freely.</p>
<p>The result? A once-convenient feature is gone, making Bluetooth speakers less versatile. While manufacturers might have their reasons, it feels like a step backward for users who relied on this functionality.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
