<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>All Posts on Deuts Log</title>
    <link>https://deuts.org/p/all/</link>
    <description>Recent content in All Posts on Deuts Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.138.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>jotuvillo@deuts.org (deuts)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>jotuvillo@deuts.org (deuts)</webMaster>
    <copyright>2024 Deuts Log</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 17:55:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://deuts.org/p/all/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Google Analytics Alternatives: Why I Chose Medama</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/medama-vs-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 17:55:00 +0800</pubDate><author>jotuvillo@deuts.org (deuts)</author>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/medama-vs-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Looking for a Google Analytics alternative, I explored several options and ultimately settled on Medama for its simplicity, lightweight nature, and ease of use. It provides essential insights without the complexity of other analytics tools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power Query Calendar Table</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/power-query-calendar-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 09:19:01 +0800</pubDate><author>jotuvillo@deuts.org (deuts)</author>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/power-query-calendar-table/</guid>
      <description>Discover the importance of a calendar table in data modeling and how it simplifies date-based analysis, advanced calculations, and filtering. Struggling with DAX bugs? Power Query offers a robust alternative for generating a dynamic calendar table effortlessly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Choose Cloudflare Access over Authelia/Authentik</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/cloudflareaccess-vs-authelia-vs-authentik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 09:37:51 +0800</pubDate><author>jotuvillo@deuts.org (deuts)</author>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/cloudflareaccess-vs-authelia-vs-authentik/</guid>
      <description>A comparison of the complexities and risks of Authelia and Authentik with the simplicity and reliability of using Cloudflare Access for application security.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did I Make a Mistake Trusting Resilio Sync for File Syncing?</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/resilio-sync-reliability-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 17:49:54 +0800</pubDate><author>jotuvillo@deuts.org (deuts)</author>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/resilio-sync-reliability-issues/</guid>
      <description>After encountering a &amp;#34;No tracker connection available&amp;#34; issue, I’m reevaluating Resilio Sync’s reliability and whether my decision to use it over Syncthing was the right one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The PLDT Horror: 72 Hours (and Counting) Without Internet</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/pldt-no-internet-downtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 09:15:54 +0800</pubDate><author>jotuvillo@deuts.org (deuts)</author>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/pldt-no-internet-downtime/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#39;s been 72 hours without internet at home, and PLDT&amp;#39;s response has been nothing short of frustrating. From an initial promise of a 36-hour restoration to delays upon delays, this post dives into the reality of dealing with their lackluster service in Salcedo Village, Makati.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Custom Caddy Docker image with Cloudflare DNS challenge support</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/caddy-docker-cloudflare-dns-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 08:11:44 +0800</pubDate><author>jotuvillo@deuts.org (deuts)</author>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/caddy-docker-cloudflare-dns-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Configure a custom Caddy Docker image to use Cloudflare’s DNS challenge, securing HTTPS without exposing ports 80/443, ideal for firewall, CGNAT, and load-balancer setups.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing Your Docker-Hosted Service with HTTP Basic Authentication in Caddy</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/docker-caddy-basic-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 21:46:40 +0800</pubDate><author>jotuvillo@deuts.org (deuts)</author>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/docker-caddy-basic-auth/</guid>
      <description>Learn to secure Docker services with Caddy’s Basic Authentication by setting up a reverse proxy to protect internal or staging containers and restrict access to specific paths.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Readability with Callouts in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/hugo-callouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 18:26:00 +0800</pubDate><author>jotuvillo@deuts.org (deuts)</author>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/hugo-callouts/</guid>
      <description>Discover how callouts can enhance readability and engagement by highlighting key information in notes or web content. Learn how to implement custom callouts in Hugo using shortcodes, making important details more accessible and memorable for your readers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an Efficient Blogging Workflow with Hugo, Obsidian, and GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/build-hugo-obsidian-github-pages-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 23:44:23 +0800</pubDate><author>jotuvillo@deuts.org (deuts)</author>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/build-hugo-obsidian-github-pages-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Exploring Hugo, Obsidian and Github Pages as a flexible and efficient blogging setup, focusing on low dependency and high control, with a look at potential WordPress migration challenges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Git Repository for Pushing to GitHub</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/git-repository-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 11:44:23 +0800</pubDate><author>jotuvillo@deuts.org (deuts)</author>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/git-repository-to-github/</guid>
      <description>Set up a Git repository with main as the initial branch, link it to GitHub with a custom remote (not origin), and authenticate using GitHub’s Personal Access Token (PAT). This guide covers staging, committing, and pushing files securely and efficiently, so you can use common Git commands without repeatedly specifying a remote.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
