<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>All Posts on Deuts Log</title>
    <link>https://deuts.org/p/all/</link>
    <description>Recent content in All Posts on Deuts Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 Deuts Log</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:09:57 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://deuts.org/p/all/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo vs. Jekyll: Which One Should You Choose?</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/hugo-vs-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:09:57 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/hugo-vs-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Wondering whether to choose Hugo or Jekyll for your static site? Read on as we compare their strengths, weaknesses, and hosting options, helping you make an informed decision based on your preferences and project requirements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Use an SSH Key for a Specific GitHub Repository</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/ssh-key-github-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 11:01:31 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/ssh-key-github-repo/</guid>
      <description>A walkthrough process of configuring SSH keys to connect to a specific GitHub repository. This setup enhances security by limiting access to just one repository, making it safer, especially when storing private keys on remote servers or VPS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Hugo’s Section Structure with `_index.md` Files</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/understanding-hugo-sections-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 13:53:32 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/understanding-hugo-sections-index/</guid>
      <description>Hugo’s sections are defined by directories containing `_index.md` files. This post explains how Hugo handles sections and subsections, including how content from a subsection’s `_index.md` appears in the parent section.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up Picsur with ShareX for Seamless Screenshot Uploading</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/picsur-sharex-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 14:25:27 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/picsur-sharex-setup/</guid>
      <description>A step-by-step guide to set up Picsur with ShareX, complete with tips for generating API keys and configuring the uploader.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Prefer SQLite-Only Docker Services</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/why-sqlite-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 13:20:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/why-sqlite-docker/</guid>
      <description>SQLite’s embedded nature eliminates the need for complex client-server setups, reducing overhead and simplifying Docker configurations. It’s lightweight, fast, and easy to set up, making it an ideal choice for solo users and low-traffic applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Friday VPS Deals: More Bang, Less Buck, and a Side of Virtual Glory</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/black-friday-vps-deals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:31:27 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/black-friday-vps-deals/</guid>
      <description>Black Friday offers unmatched VPS deals, perfect for expanding your digital empire. RackNerd’s discounts showcase the jaw-dropping value this season provides.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Google Analytics Alternatives: Why I Chose Medama</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/medama-vs-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 17:55:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/medama-vs-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Looking for a Google Analytics alternative, I explored several options and ultimately settled on Medama for its simplicity, lightweight nature, and ease of use. It provides essential insights without the complexity of other analytics tools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power Query Calendar Table</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/power-query-calendar-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 09:19:01 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/power-query-calendar-table/</guid>
      <description>Discover the importance of a calendar table in data modeling and how it simplifies date-based analysis, advanced calculations, and filtering. Struggling with DAX bugs? Power Query offers a robust alternative for generating a dynamic calendar table effortlessly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Choose Cloudflare Access over Authelia/Authentik</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/cloudflareaccess-vs-authelia-vs-authentik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 09:37:51 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/cloudflareaccess-vs-authelia-vs-authentik/</guid>
      <description>A comparison of the complexities and risks of Authelia and Authentik with the simplicity and reliability of using Cloudflare Access for application security.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did I Make a Mistake Trusting Resilio Sync for File Syncing?</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/resilio-sync-reliability-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 17:49:54 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/resilio-sync-reliability-issues/</guid>
      <description>After encountering a &amp;#34;No tracker connection available&amp;#34; issue, I’m reevaluating Resilio Sync’s reliability and whether my decision to use it over Syncthing was the right one.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
