<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet on Deuts Log</title>
    <link>https://deuts.org/t/internet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet on Deuts Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 Deuts Log</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 23:32:45 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://deuts.org/t/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GFiber Prepaid 100 Mbps</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/x/gfiber-prepaid-100-mbps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 23:32:45 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/x/gfiber-prepaid-100-mbps/</guid>
      <description>If Globe consistently delivers 50 Mbps, it would more than meet my daily needs, proving that reliability often outshines raw speed.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="post-entry">
    <a href="https://www.yugatech.com/news/gfiber-prepaid-100-mbps-prepaid-fiber-plan-launched/" target="_blank" class="linkcard-wrapper">
      <div class="linkcard-content">
        <h3 class="linkcard-title">GFiber Prepaid 100 Mbps fiber plans launched</h3>
        <p class="linkcard-description">Globe has launched GFiber Prepaid 100 Mbps plans designed for value-conscious users, offering flexible options like 7-day, 30-day, or yearly subscriptions without long-term contracts. With stable, low-latency connections ideal for 4K streaming, gaming, and large file transfers, these plans balance affordability and performance for diverse needs.</p>
      </div>
    </a>
  </div>
  
<p>If Globe can consistently deliver 50 Mbps, it would easily cover most of my everyday needs. After all, whether it’s streaming in HD, handling work tasks, or indulging in a bit of online gaming, reliable speed beats sheer numbers any day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The PLDT Horror: 72 Hours (and Counting) Without Internet</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/pldt-no-internet-downtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 09:15:54 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/pldt-no-internet-downtime/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#39;s been 72 hours without internet at home, and PLDT&amp;#39;s response has been nothing short of frustrating. From an initial promise of a 36-hour restoration to delays upon delays, this post dives into the reality of dealing with their lackluster service in Salcedo Village, Makati.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just when I thought I was done blogging about bad services, here I am again. I couldn&rsquo;t resist letting this one out.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s been almost 3 days without internet at home in Salcedo Village, Makati. The provider? None other than the <em>reliable</em> PLDT.</p>
<p>Their initial response when I reported the issue? I was assigned a ticket stating restoration may take—wait for it—up to 36 <em>hours</em>. Not great, but manageable, right? Fast forward 72 hours (double the time promised), and what do I get? A message saying they&rsquo;ll provide an <em>update</em> (not even a fix!) within another 48 hours.</p>
<p>PLDT, it seems, has no sense of urgency to address the concerns of its paying customers. If you&rsquo;re in the internet provider business, 1 day of downtime might be acceptable, but <em>three</em> days? That&rsquo;s absurd.</p>
<p>Now, thanks to PLDT’s stellar service, I’m forced to use my mobile hotspot for the weekend. What a bummer. I’ll be eating into my phone’s data provision just to get work done. Honestly, PLDT should be the one footing the bill for my backup internet.</p>
<p>And let’s not forget their audacity to lock customers into 3-year contracts! I wish Converge had been available in my building when I was shopping for wired internet 10 months ago. At least I&rsquo;d have a shot at better service.</p>
<p>So, PLDT service is <em>actually</em> this bad, huh? I always thought those horror stories were just urban myths—tales spun to scare unsuspecting subscribers. But nope, they’re real. And here I am, starring in my own PLDT nightmare.</p>
<h3 id="update-11172024-613am">Update 11/17/2024 6:13am</h3>
<p>After 85 hours of downtime, my PLDT internet was finally back online.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
