<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Greencloud on Deuts Log</title>
    <link>https://deuts.org/t/greencloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Greencloud on Deuts Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 Deuts Log</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:59:59 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://deuts.org/t/greencloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The True Cost of Cheap VPS</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/the-true-cost-of-cheap-vps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:59:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/the-true-cost-of-cheap-vps/</guid>
      <description>GreenCloud&amp;#39;s recent migration process highlights the hidden costs of cheap VPS hosting. While the price may be attractive, the burden of manual tasks like backups, system reinstallation, and DNS updates falls on the customer, turning what should be a seamless process into a time-consuming hassle.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Choosing an affordable VPS provider can save money, but it often comes with extra work and frustration. GreenCloud’s recent migration from SolusVM to VirtFusion is a prime example. Here&rsquo;s the email they sent:</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Subject: [GreenCloud] Control Panel Migration on the MILAN2SG1 node</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Dear Customer,</p>
<p>As part of our service improvement, we are migrating from our current control panel (SolusVM) to a new, modern, and user-friendly control panel called VirtFusion, which offers advanced features such as Backup/Snapshot, SSH Key management, Custom ISOs and more.</p>
<p>Since this is a manual process, so we kindly ask you to back up your VPS on the MILAN2SG1 node and notify us once this is done so we can create a new VPS on VirtFusion for you. If needed, we can retain your old IPv4 address. Please open a ticket with our Technical Department when you&rsquo;re ready. Please do not reply to this email directly as it might go to our Spam/Junk folder.</p>
<p>If you prefer to remain on SolusVM, a migration may be required to merge with our available SolusVM nodes. We will notify you with a schedule at that time. Kindly let us know your decision within 10 days of receiving this email.</p>
<p>Best regards,<br>
GreenCloud Team</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><strong>The Hassle of Migration</strong></p>
<p>Instead of a smooth transition, GreenCloud’s migration process places the burden on customers:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Manual Backups</strong><br>
No tools or instructions for backing up data. Customers must do it themselves.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Reinstallation of Systems</strong><br>
A complete OS reinstall means customers need to manually restore backups and reconfigure their setups.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Changing IP Address and DNS Records</strong><br>
Most likely, a new IP address will be assigned, forcing customers to update DNS records manually and endure service downtime.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>GreenCloud’s approach to migration highlights the real cost of cheap VPS hosting: when the price is low, customers are often left to deal with the burdens and frustrations that providers should be handling, disrupting services and causing unnecessary hassle.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
