<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Vps-Hosting on Deuts Log</title>
    <link>https://deuts.org/t/vps-hosting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vps-Hosting on Deuts Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 Deuts Log</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 08:40:14 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://deuts.org/t/vps-hosting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The story of a fly-by-night VPS host</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/slicehosting-fly-by-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 08:40:14 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/slicehosting-fly-by-night/</guid>
      <description>Slicehosting abruptly closed its doors, citing management challenges. While they promised refunds, my experience with their slow storage and frequent downtimes highlights the risks of trusting fly-by-night VPS providers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Friday VPS Deals: More Bang, Less Buck, and a Side of Virtual Glory</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/black-friday-vps-deals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:31:27 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/black-friday-vps-deals/</guid>
      <description>Black Friday offers unmatched VPS deals, perfect for expanding your digital empire. RackNerd’s discounts showcase the jaw-dropping value this season provides.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checklist of things to do on a new VPS server</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/new-vps-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 16:40:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/new-vps-checklist/</guid>
      <description>This guide walks through the process of setting up a fresh Linux system and installing essential tools, Docker, Docker Compose, Cloudflare Tunnel, Portainer, and Duplicati. It includes instructions for updating the system, changing the root password, adding a non-root user, setting the timezone, and installing Docker. Additionally, it provides detailed steps for configuring Docker containers for Cloudflare Tunnel, Portainer (for managing Docker containers), and Duplicati (for backup), all set up with a cloudflared network bridge to securely expose the apps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to install Hugo in a Linux VPS</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/hugo-linux-vps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 10:43:30 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/hugo-linux-vps/</guid>
      <description>This post explains how to install Hugo on Debian or Ubuntu. It covers installing an older version via APT, as well as installing the latest version from GitHub by downloading the .deb file, installing it, and ensuring the binary is properly copied to the /usr/bin/ directory. It also includes instructions for updating Hugo to the latest release.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Joplin work with Nginx Proxy Manager and Duplicati (Docker)</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/joplin-npm-duplicati-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 22:03:23 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/joplin-npm-duplicati-docker/</guid>
      <description>A guide on setting up a Joplin server using Docker Compose, including benefits like faster syncing, easy note sharing, and user access. It covers steps for creating a Docker network, configuring Nginx Proxy Manager, setting up the app and database, and managing backups with Duplicati. Troubleshooting steps for connection issues between Joplin and PostgreSQL are also provided.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Movies and TV Shows on Kodi</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/streaming-movies-tv-shows-kodi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 21:28:50 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/streaming-movies-tv-shows-kodi/</guid>
      <description>You can set up Kodi to stream media from a VPS or local server using Apache or Nginx. See the video for details on adding remote media sources in Kodi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contabo Price Increase 2022</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/contabo-price-increase-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 08:41:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/contabo-price-increase-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contabo is raising my fee from EUR 4.99 to EUR 5.99 starting November 1. I&amp;#39;ll continue using it for my Plex and other services, but will check for Black Friday deals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Cloud Free Tier</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/oracle-cloud-free-tier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 08:45:44 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/oracle-cloud-free-tier/</guid>
      <description>A tutorial on Oracle Cloud Free Tier, but be cautious: trust issues with Oracle and potential Docker compatibility problems due to ARM architecture. Also, encountered the &amp;#34;Out of capacity&amp;#34; error when signing up.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
