<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mastodon on Deuts Log</title>
    <link>https://deuts.org/a/mastodon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mastodon on Deuts Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 Deuts Log</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:16:48 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://deuts.org/a/mastodon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why is Running Mastodon via Docker So Complicated?</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/x/running-mastodon-via-docker-complicated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:16:48 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/x/running-mastodon-via-docker-complicated/</guid>
      <description>A rant about the convoluted process of setting up Mastodon using Docker and the frustration of dealing with multiple dependencies and configurations.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m wishing I could host my own Mastodon instance, but setting it up with Docker is unnecessarily complicated. There are countless dependencies to handle, multiple services to configure, and numerous potential points of failure. For a platform of its size, you&rsquo;d expect a more straightforward, user-friendly Docker setup, but it&rsquo;s anything but. Why is this process so difficult to get right?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Mastodon on Debian 11 Without Docker</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/install-mastodon-debian-11-without-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 10:26:42 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/install-mastodon-debian-11-without-docker/</guid>
      <description>This post outlines the steps for installing Mastodon on Debian 11 without Docker, including setting up dependencies like PostgreSQL, Redis, and Yarn, cloning the Mastodon repository, configuring the environment, and starting the server. The user plans to try it and provide feedback.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With all the hype about ChatGPT nowadays, I really have to try it. And I&rsquo;m still wondering how to install Mastodon on Debian 11 without Docker. And here&rsquo;s the AI&rsquo;s response:</p>
<h2 id="how-to-install-mastodon-on-debian-11-without-docker-instructions-generated-from-chatgpt">How to Install Mastodon on Debian 11 Without Docker (instructions generated from ChatGPT)</h2>
<p>To install Mastodon, the open-source, decentralized social networking platform, on Debian 11 without using Docker, you can follow these steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>First, make sure you have the necessary dependencies installed on your system. This includes PostgreSQL, Redis, and Yarn. You can install these using the following commands:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install postgresql postgresql-contrib
sudo apt-get install redis-server
curl -sS https://dl.yarnpkg.com/debian/pubkey.gpg | sudo apt-key add -
echo &#34;deb https://dl.yarnpkg.com/debian/ stable main&#34; | sudo tee /etc/apt/sources.list.d/yarn.list
sudo apt-get update &amp;&amp; sudo apt-get install yarn
</code></pre><ol start="2">
<li>Next, clone the Mastodon Git repository to your local machine using the following command:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>git clone https://github.com/tootsuite/mastodon.git
</code></pre><ol start="3">
<li>Navigate to the Mastodon directory and install the necessary dependencies using Yarn:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>cd mastodon
yarn install
</code></pre><ol start="4">
<li>
<p>Next, you will need to configure Mastodon by copying the .env.production.sample file to .env.production and editing it to set the appropriate values for your environment. This includes setting up your database, caching, and other options.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Once the configuration is complete, you can compile the Mastodon assets using the following command:</p>
</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>RAILS_ENV=production bundle exec rails assets:precompile
</code></pre><ol start="6">
<li>Finally, you can start the Mastodon server using the following command:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>RAILS_ENV=production bundle exec rails s
</code></pre><p>Mastodon should now be running on your system. You can access it in your web browser at <code>http://localhost:3000</code>.</p>
<p>Note: The steps outlined above are a simplified version of the installation instructions for Mastodon. For more detailed instructions and additional options, please refer to the Mastodon documentation.</p>
<h2 id="i-still-have-to-try-this">I still have to try this</h2>
<p>And I still have to try this soon. Will provide feedback if this instuction prove helpful.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
