<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Magicdns on Deuts Log</title>
    <link>https://deuts.org/t/magicdns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Magicdns on Deuts Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 Deuts Log</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 13:02:41 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://deuts.org/t/magicdns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tailscale Accept DNS Settings</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/tailscale-accept-dns-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 13:02:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/tailscale-accept-dns-settings/</guid>
      <description>Tailscale automatically manages DNS settings, but you may prefer to use local DNS servers. Find out how to disable Tailscale DNS on Linux and how the process differs on Windows.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you install Tailscale on a Linux server and run the <code>sudo tailscale up</code> command, it automatically enables DNS management with the setting <code>--accept-dns=true</code>. This forces Tailscale to handle DNS resolution, which may not always be what you want.</p>
<p>By default, when you enable <strong>MagicDNS</strong> in the Tailscale admin panel, it overwrites your <code>/etc/resolv.conf</code> file with its DNS server <code>100.100.100.100</code>. If you add a custom nameserver and enable <strong>Override local DNS</strong>, Tailscale will apply that DNS server across all devices in your Tailnet. This is useful if you’re using services like Pi-Hole or NextDNS.</p>
<p>But what if you want to disable Tailscale DNS on certain devices and revert to local DNS settings?</p>
<h2 id="disabling-tailscale-dns-on-linux">Disabling Tailscale DNS on Linux</h2>
<p>To disable Tailscale&rsquo;s DNS management on Linux, run:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sudo tailscale set --accept-dns<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>false
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>This command will revert your <code>/etc/resolv.conf</code> to the DNS values it had before Tailscale was installed, like <code>1.1.1.1</code> or <code>8.8.8.8</code>. Your Linux server will no longer be affected by Tailscale&rsquo;s DNS settings, which is useful if you prefer to manage DNS locally, particularly on a VPS where misconfigurations, either in the DNS settings or the ACL, can be problematic.</p>
<h2 id="tailscale-dns-on-windows">Tailscale DNS on Windows</h2>
<p>On Windows, this process is easier, as there&rsquo;s a simple checkbox to disable Tailscale DNS in the system tray preferences. This GUI option offers a more straightforward way to adjust DNS settings without needing terminal commands.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Tailscale’s DNS management is convenient, but sometimes you may need to regain control over DNS settings. Disabling Tailscale DNS on Linux is a quick way to ensure your server uses local DNS settings, keeping your configuration simple and reliable.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
