<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Authelia on Deuts Log</title>
    <link>https://deuts.org/a/authelia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authelia on Deuts Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 Deuts Log</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 09:37:51 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://deuts.org/a/authelia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Choose Cloudflare Access over Authelia/Authentik</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/cloudflareaccess-vs-authelia-vs-authentik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 09:37:51 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/cloudflareaccess-vs-authelia-vs-authentik/</guid>
      <description>A comparison of the complexities and risks of Authelia and Authentik with the simplicity and reliability of using Cloudflare Access for application security.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to securing your applications, the choice often boils down to what best fits your needs and resources. After exploring my options, I decided that Cloudflare Access was the right tool for the job.</p>
<h3 id="the-complexity-of-authelia-and-authentik">The Complexity of Authelia and Authentik</h3>
<p>Authelia and Authentik are robust tools for managing application security, but using them comes with several challenges:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Complex Setup</strong>: Setting up either solution requires multiple Docker containers—typically three or four—for just a single instance.</li>
<li><strong>Server Overhead</strong>: Running these extra containers means higher resource consumption, which can strain your server and add unnecessary maintenance.</li>
<li><strong>Single Point of Failure</strong>: These systems act as gatekeepers for your applications. If they go down, so does access to all your apps—even simple, low-risk ones. This creates a dependency that adds unnecessary risk, especially for small-scale projects.</li>
<li><strong>Time Investment</strong>: Learning to configure and maintain these systems demands significant time and effort—something not always feasible for smaller projects.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="why-i-chose-cloudflare-access">Why I Chose Cloudflare Access</h3>
<p>Rather than spending my time managing self-hosted tools like Authelia or Authentik, I turned to Cloudflare Access. Here’s what makes it stand out:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Centralized Management</strong>: Cloudflare Access provides a unified dashboard to easily manage all your applications in one place.</li>
<li><strong>Straightforward Setup</strong>: There’s no need for additional containers or a complicated configuration process—just a few steps and you’re up and running.</li>
<li><strong>Domain-Level Implementation</strong>: Cloudflare Access is implemented directly at the domain or subdomain level, eliminating the need to spin up yet another Docker container to manage access. This makes it lightweight and efficient.</li>
<li><strong>Built-In Resilience</strong>: Unlike Authelia or Authentik, Cloudflare Access avoids creating a single point of failure. Cloudflare’s globally distributed infrastructure ensures that your applications remain available, even in the face of disruptions.</li>
<li><strong>Seamless Integration</strong>: It works smoothly with popular identity providers like Google Workspace and GitHub, simplifying authentication management.</li>
<li><strong>Zero Trust Security</strong>: Cloudflare Access includes powerful features like Zero Trust policies and device posture checks, ensuring only authorized users can access your applications.</li>
<li><strong>Bonus Benefits</strong>: Using Cloudflare Access means leveraging Cloudflare’s network for additional perks like DDoS protection and improved application performance.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="why-it-might-be-right-for-you">Why It Might Be Right for You</h3>
<p>If your goal is to simplify application security without sacrificing reliability, Cloudflare Access is an excellent choice. It eliminates the complexity of self-hosted solutions, reduces server overhead, and removes the risk of losing access due to a single point of failure.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
