<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>All Posts on Deuts Log</title>
    <link>https://deuts.org/p/</link>
    <description>Recent content in All Posts on Deuts Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.138.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 08:11:44 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://deuts.org/p/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Custom Caddy Docker image with Cloudflare DNS challenge support</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/caddy-docker-cloudflare-dns-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 08:11:44 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/caddy-docker-cloudflare-dns-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Configure a custom Caddy Docker image to use Cloudflare’s DNS challenge, securing HTTPS without exposing ports 80/443, ideal for firewall, CGNAT, and load-balancer setups.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing Your Docker-Hosted Service with HTTP Basic Authentication in Caddy</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/docker-caddy-basic-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 21:46:40 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/docker-caddy-basic-auth/</guid>
      <description>Learn to secure Docker services with Caddy’s Basic Authentication by setting up a reverse proxy to protect internal or staging containers and restrict access to specific paths.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Readability with Callouts in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/hugo-callouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 18:26:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/hugo-callouts/</guid>
      <description>Discover how callouts can enhance readability and engagement by highlighting key information in notes or web content. Learn how to implement custom callouts in Hugo using shortcodes, making important details more accessible and memorable for your readers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an Efficient Blogging Workflow with Hugo, Obsidian, and GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/build-hugo-obsidian-github-pages-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 23:44:23 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/build-hugo-obsidian-github-pages-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Exploring Hugo, Obsidian and Github Pages as a flexible and efficient blogging setup, focusing on low dependency and high control, with a look at potential WordPress migration challenges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Git Repository for Pushing to GitHub</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/git-repository-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 11:44:23 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/git-repository-to-github/</guid>
      <description>Set up a Git repository with main as the initial branch, link it to GitHub with a custom remote (not origin), and authenticate using GitHub’s Personal Access Token (PAT). This guide covers staging, committing, and pushing files securely and efficiently, so you can use common Git commands without repeatedly specifying a remote.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hugo and Obsidian workflow</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/hugo-and-obsidian-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 21:44:50 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/hugo-and-obsidian-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Highlights of issues with Obsidian plugins like Hugo Publish and Static Site MD Exporter when used in a Hugo blogging workflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using List.Generate to Generate Running Total Column in Power Query</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/list-generate-running-total/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 21:23:57 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/list-generate-running-total/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a quicker, cleaner way to generate a running total in Power Query—no need for complex formulas or multiple steps! With this streamlined approach, you can set up a cumulative total in record time, saving both processing power and patience. Say goodbye to endless column configurations and hello to efficiency!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samba Docker or Native</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/samba-on-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 17:41:18 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/samba-on-docker/</guid>
      <description>This post discusses the advantages of using Docker for Samba over native implementation, highlighting the convenience of portability and easier reinstallation with Docker Compose files. The author reflects on their past experience with native Samba setups and shares resources for a Docker-based Samba implementation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Docker Apps to Install</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/my-docker-apps-to-install-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 22:41:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/my-docker-apps-to-install-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>This post shares the author&amp;#39;s inspiration from Jim’s Garage on YouTube and his GitHub repository to try out several Docker applications: Immich, Paperless-ngx, Vikunja, rClone, and Restic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update on Vikunja</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/vikunja-update-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 22:19:57 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/vikunja-update-2024/</guid>
      <description>This post discusses a recent change in the Docker installation of Vikunja, where a separate API container is no longer required. The author is considering starting to use Vikunja and plans to adapt the provided Docker Compose file (originally using Traefik) to their own setup with NPM as the reverse proxy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Most Faked Foods In The World</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/most-faked-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 07:58:13 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/most-faked-food/</guid>
      <description>The video from Insider Business lists the 11 most faked foods in the world, such as truffles, maple syrup, wasabi, and parmesan cheese. The author reflects on their personal consumption, admitting to probably buying fake parmesan cheese, honey, and olive oil, and plans to be more cautious during future grocery trips.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Smoothie Diet Scam</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/the-smoothie-diet-scam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 15:17:55 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/the-smoothie-diet-scam/</guid>
      <description>The author warns against falling for scams promoted by YouTube shorts, particularly those advertising The Smoothie Diet. They explain that these smoothies are often high in sugar and ineffective for weight loss. Instead, the author advocates for intermittent fasting, particularly the &amp;#34;clean&amp;#34; fast, as a free and effective strategy. They recommend looking into the benefits of fasting and reading Gin Stephens&amp;#39; books Fast, Feast, Repeat and Delay, Don&amp;#39;t Deny for more guidance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Analysis with Python for Excel Users</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/data-analysis-python-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 08:58:29 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/data-analysis-python-excel/</guid>
      <description>The post shares the author’s intention to learn Python to reinforce their data analysis skills and invites others to join in starting with a 4-hour free course on YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I can&#39;t make Vikunja work on my set up</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/vikunja-internal-server-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 19:04:11 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/vikunja-internal-server-error/</guid>
      <description>Vikunja is a feature-rich open-source todo app, but installing it via Docker requires multiple containers. The author faced frequent Internal Server Errors and API issues when using docker-compose, even after adding Redis. Frustrated by the ongoing errors, the author ultimately removed the setup entirely.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A few Nextcloud post-installation configurations</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/nextcloud-post-install-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 08:33:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/nextcloud-post-install-config/</guid>
      <description>Nextcloud installation via Docker may show warnings for service discovery and cron jobs. To fix the service discovery issue, update the .htaccess file. For cron jobs, set up a cron task on the host system to run cron.php every 5 minutes in the Nextcloud container.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checklist of things to do on a new VPS server</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/new-vps-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 16:40:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/new-vps-checklist/</guid>
      <description>This guide walks through the process of setting up a fresh Linux system and installing essential tools, Docker, Docker Compose, Cloudflare Tunnel, Portainer, and Duplicati. It includes instructions for updating the system, changing the root password, adding a non-root user, setting the timezone, and installing Docker. Additionally, it provides detailed steps for configuring Docker containers for Cloudflare Tunnel, Portainer (for managing Docker containers), and Duplicati (for backup), all set up with a cloudflared network bridge to securely expose the apps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to install Hugo in a Linux VPS</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/hugo-linux-vps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 10:43:30 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/hugo-linux-vps/</guid>
      <description>This post explains how to install Hugo on Debian or Ubuntu. It covers installing an older version via APT, as well as installing the latest version from GitHub by downloading the .deb file, installing it, and ensuring the binary is properly copied to the /usr/bin/ directory. It also includes instructions for updating Hugo to the latest release.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Docker Command to Check the Sizes of your Containers</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/docker-container-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 08:07:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/docker-container-size/</guid>
      <description>This post provides a quick way to check the size of Docker containers using the docker ps --size command and refines it to show only relevant columns—Container ID, Names, Image, and Size—by using the --format option.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Is Stored in Legacy Trusted.gpg Keyring</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/key-legacy-trusted-gpg-keyring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 08:21:31 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/key-legacy-trusted-gpg-keyring/</guid>
      <description>This post addresses the issue of legacy keyrings on fresh installs of Debian or Ubuntu, where an error message warns about keys stored in the deprecated trusted.gpg keyring. The solution is to copy the keyring to the trusted.gpg.d directory and update the system using sudo apt update.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Rescan Your Docker Nextcloud Folders</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/how-to-rescan-docker-nextcloud-folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 21:50:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/how-to-rescan-docker-nextcloud-folders/</guid>
      <description>If you can&amp;#39;t see files or subfolders in Nextcloud after creating them or restoring from a backup, running the command docker exec -u www-data nextcloud_app php occ files:scan --all will fix the issue. This works for Nextcloud version 27.0.1 when installed via Docker.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Underrated TV Shows of 2022 Et Al</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/underrated-tv-shows-2022-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 19:20:35 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/underrated-tv-shows-2022-et-al/</guid>
      <description>These underrated TV shows from 2022 are worth checking out. The True Story of the LA Lakers dives into the history of the Lakers with rich stories and insightful interviews.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power Query Table.Skip While Row Is Blank</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/power-query-table-skip-while-row-is-blank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 17:36:50 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/power-query-table-skip-while-row-is-blank/</guid>
      <description>This post explains how to use the Table.Skip function in Power Query to dynamically skip rows with null values in a specified column, making the process flexible across files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Mastodon on Debian 11 Without Docker</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/install-mastodon-debian-11-without-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 10:26:42 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/install-mastodon-debian-11-without-docker/</guid>
      <description>This post outlines the steps for installing Mastodon on Debian 11 without Docker, including setting up dependencies like PostgreSQL, Redis, and Yarn, cloning the Mastodon repository, configuring the environment, and starting the server. The user plans to try it and provide feedback.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yet another iPhone vs. Android post</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/iphone-vs-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 12:11:31 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/iphone-vs-android/</guid>
      <description>This discusses why I prefer Android over Apple, highlighting key features that are indispensable to me, such as dual SIM, torrenting apps, Syncthing, USB Type-C, customizable home screens, expandable storage, and dual accounts/profile. I also critique iMessage and Airdrop, explaining their preferences for alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Bitcoin Is a Scam</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/why-bitcoin-is-a-scam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 21:50:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/why-bitcoin-is-a-scam/</guid>
      <description>Bitcoin is often seen more as an investment than a currency. People rarely use it for transactions; instead, they buy it with the expectation that others will do the same, driving up its price. This behavior is also common with other cryptocurrencies, which some compare to a Ponzi scheme.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Joplin work with Nginx Proxy Manager and Duplicati (Docker)</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/joplin-npm-duplicati-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 22:03:23 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/joplin-npm-duplicati-docker/</guid>
      <description>A guide on setting up a Joplin server using Docker Compose, including benefits like faster syncing, easy note sharing, and user access. It covers steps for creating a Docker network, configuring Nginx Proxy Manager, setting up the app and database, and managing backups with Duplicati. Troubleshooting steps for connection issues between Joplin and PostgreSQL are also provided.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Movies and TV Shows on Kodi</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/streaming-movies-tv-shows-kodi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 21:28:50 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/streaming-movies-tv-shows-kodi/</guid>
      <description>You can set up Kodi to stream media from a VPS or local server using Apache or Nginx. See the video for details on adding remote media sources in Kodi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TV Shows I May Consider Watching in the Future</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/tv-shows-consider-watching-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 12:24:06 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/tv-shows-consider-watching-future/</guid>
      <description>Shows I removed from Sonarr but may follow again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GT Metrix Comparison of my 3 Websites</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/gt-metrix-comparison-3-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 09:40:50 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/gt-metrix-comparison-3-websites/</guid>
      <description>A GTMetrix comparison shows Hugo (deuts.org) outperforms WordPress (deuts.net and chesshive.com), proving the efficiency of static site generators for better site speed and user experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notion vs Airtable</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/notion-vs-airtable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 09:21:08 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/notion-vs-airtable/</guid>
      <description>Notion is primarily a note-taking tool with basic database functions, while Airtable is more suited for databases and workflows with a powerful API for integrations, including Excel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can This Old Laptop Handle Plex?</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/can-old-laptop-handle-plex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 22:14:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/can-old-laptop-handle-plex/</guid>
      <description>A 7th-gen i5 laptop should easily handle Plex, even for 4K streams. A low-spec Beelink S1 Mini PC (Celeron N3450) runs Plex and several Docker services without issue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Bash Script and Make it Executable?</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/create-bash-script-executable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 20:55:43 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/create-bash-script-executable/</guid>
      <description>Create a bash script to easily run long commands, like hugo server, by saving them in a file, making it executable, and running the script.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ano Ang Nasa Dakong Paroon</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/ano-ang-nasa-dakong-paroon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 15:15:07 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/ano-ang-nasa-dakong-paroon/</guid>
      <description>Gabi ng lagim</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contabo Price Increase 2022</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/contabo-price-increase-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 08:41:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/contabo-price-increase-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contabo is raising my fee from EUR 4.99 to EUR 5.99 starting November 1. I&amp;#39;ll continue using it for my Plex and other services, but will check for Black Friday deals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basketball Video Games Evolution</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/basketball-video-games-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 23:03:33 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/basketball-video-games-evolution/</guid>
      <description>This video showcases basketball video game interfaces from 1974, bringing back memories of Double Dribble and NBA Live 2004 office LAN tournaments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BPI USD/PHP Outlook 2023</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/bpi-usd-php-outlook-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 15:47:37 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/bpi-usd-php-outlook-2023/</guid>
      <description>BPI&amp;#39;s outlook is quite aggressive, forecasting a steady weakening of the PHP against the USD, reaching 60.521 by Q4 2023.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Cloud Free Tier</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/oracle-cloud-free-tier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 08:45:44 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/oracle-cloud-free-tier/</guid>
      <description>A tutorial on Oracle Cloud Free Tier, but be cautious: trust issues with Oracle and potential Docker compatibility problems due to ARM architecture. Also, encountered the &amp;#34;Out of capacity&amp;#34; error when signing up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nico &amp; Vinz - Am I Wrong</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/nico-vinz-am-i-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 08:50:47 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/nico-vinz-am-i-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Sounds like the perfect motto for anyone who’s always the life of the debate!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excel Stockhistory Function Pro Tips</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/excel-stockhistory-function-pro-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 14:08:44 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/excel-stockhistory-function-pro-tips/</guid>
      <description>Better late than never! The STOCKHISTORY function is a game-changer for tracking your stock portfolio directly in Excel. It’s like having a personal financial assistant that never sleeps!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beef Fast Food Recipes</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/beef-fast-food-recipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 13:44:03 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/beef-fast-food-recipes/</guid>
      <description>Looks like your kitchen’s about to turn into a Bulgogi buffet—time to beef up those recipes!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blood vs. Name</title>
      <link>https://deuts.org/p/blood-vs-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 13:01:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deuts.org/p/blood-vs-name/</guid>
      <description>A powerful reminder that what we leave behind is often more about our legacy and reputation than the battles we&amp;#39;ve fought.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
